准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
最美好的一天
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
创意总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
太阳当空照  朝我微微笑
Mr. Sun came up and he smiled at me
说今天真美好  一起等着瞧
Said, "it's gonna be a good one, just wait and see"
跳下了床
Jumped out of bed
径直跑出门  多欣喜若狂
And I ran outside feeling so extra-ecstatified
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
小蜗
Hey, Gary
你问今天为什么是最美好的一天
"Why is this the best day ever," you ask?
因为小蜗
Because, Gary
我在这美好的一天里  要先开始
I get to start this wonderful day
给新一代美味的蟹黄堡带来新生
bringing life to a whole new generation
of delicious Krabby Patties
中午再跟珊迪精力充沛地来场空手道
Followed by a vigorous midday session
of karate with Sandy
下午跟派大星捉水母
And an afternoon jellyfishing with Patrick
到那里我会拿出我最新最珍贵的宝贝
where I'll unveil my newest, most prized possession
豪华捉水母复合专业网
the deluxe jelly-slayer composite pro
最后再来场压轴好戏
And for the grand finale
我所有最亲近的朋友们
every one of my closest friends
都要一起来欣赏章鱼哥的竖笛演奏会
joining together for Squidward's clarinet recital
我已经兴奋到要爆炸了
I am so excited I think I'm gonna explode
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
蟹堡王
美好一天
Best day ever
危房
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
别挡在那里  小子
Get out of the way, boy
蟹堡王已经被鉴定为危房了
Me building's been condemned, boy
这里可是闹了一大堆的线虫
We got ourselves a nematode infestation
可是
But
最美好的一天应该从蟹堡王开始才对
The best day ever starts at the Krusty Krab
各位  我很抱歉
Guys, I'm sorry
得请你们离开了
but I'm gonna have to ask you to leave
各位
Guys
你们毁了
You're ruining the
最美好
Best day
等等  不对
Wait, no
最美好的
Best day, um
继续吹  小子
Keep playin', lad
让那些害虫离我蟹堡王远一点
Take the devilish sons of the sea
away from me restaurant
得去珊迪家
I gotta get to Sandy's
等着让珊迪瞧瞧这双超黏空手道手套
Wait till Sandy gets a load of
these adhesive karate gloves
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你到底在干什么
What on earth are you doin'?
只是一点小东西  我管这叫空手道
Just a little somethin' I like to call karate
我现在没空  海绵宝宝
I can't right now, SpongeBob
屋顶破了个洞  而且大得不得了
I got a leak in my roof
the size of a full-grown quarter horse
明白
I see
那好吧  我等会儿再来
OK, then, I'll come back later
不
Knock
要
It
闹
Off
不漏了
It stopped?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
怎么了
Yeah?
你撑住
Hang on
我要去拿密封胶跟泥铲来
I'm goin' to get some sealant and patch-n-trowel
没蟹黄堡  没空手道
No krabby patties, no karate
但至少还能捉水母  陪着
But at least I still have jellyfishing with-
他已经在那开捉了
There he is now
等等我  派大星
Wait for me, Patrick
我有个全新的
I've got a brand-new
怎么了  派大星
What's wrong, Patrick?
我网断了
I broke my net
那你走运了  我带了我的旧网
Well, lucky for you, I brought my old net
要给我吗
For me?
反正我也用不着
Yeah, I won't be needin' it
毕竟我有了全新的
now that I got my brand-new
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
被我弄断了
I broke
我能用这把吗
Can I use this one?
其实吧  派大星
Well, actually, Patrick
那是我全新的网
that's my brand-new net
是吗
Yeah?
派大星  现在到我了
OK, Patrick, it's my turn, now
派大星
Hey, Patrick?
派大星老兄弟
Pat, old buddy?
派  派大星
Pat, Patrick
现在  现在到我了
it's, it's my turn now
看来还是音乐会见吧
I guess I'll see you at the concert
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
这最美好的一天不太顺利
This "best day ever" isn't goin' so good
没工作  没空手道
No work, no karate
没捉水母
no jellyfishing
至少还有章鱼哥的音乐会
I still have Squidward's concert
绝不能让这次机会白白溜走
I won't let this one slip through my fingers
活动中心隆重介绍
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
章鱼哥  怎么了
Squidward, what's wrong?
音乐会全毁了
The concert is ruined
我簧片坏了  你看
My reed is shot, see?
我完蛋了
I'm finished
给我振作起来
Pull yourself together, man
我是来听音乐会的
I came here for a concert
不管怎样都得让我听到
and darn it, I am gonna get one
可我的簧片
But my reed
快吹
Now play
可是
But
给我吹
I said play
还不错
Not bad
快进去  给我来场难忘的音乐会
Now get in there and give me a concert to remember
你这是想去哪  小子
Where do you think you're goin', kid?
我要看章鱼哥吹竖笛
I'm gonna see Squidward play his clarinet
今天是我最美好的一天
Today's my best day ever
你票呢
Where's your ticket?
一张票马上就来  船长
One ticket comin' right up, cap'n
一定就在这里面某处的
Must be in here somewhere
我没票
I don't have a ticket
没票禁止入内
No ticket, no entry
可是
But
没票禁止入内
No ticket, no entry
天啊
"Oh, dear
我没票
I don't have a ticket
可我想看音乐会
But I want to go to the show"
要怎么办呢
"What should I do?"
有了
"I know
从后门溜进去就行了
I'll just sneak in the back door"
你休想
Oh, no, you don't
海绵宝宝  你可真是
SpongeBob, you are so
请出示门票
"Ticket, please"
门票  女士
Ticket, ma'am
没问题
Certainly
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你
You
这回我一定要
This time I'm gonna
等一下  你说海绵宝宝吗
Wait a minute, did you say SpongeBob?
就那个海绵宝宝方裤裤
SpongeBob SquarePants?
你在贵宾名单里
You're on the VIP list
保留
有保留席
A reserved seat
就在我朋友旁边
Next to my friends
总算进来了
I made it
我就只要坐下来
All I have to do is sit down and
不要
No
不行  还没结束
No, it is not over
今天本来应该是我完美的一天才对
This was supposed to be my perfect day
结果一切都
But then everything
坐下
Sit down
结果一切都急转直下
Then everything turned to doo-doo
没事的  海绵宝宝
It's OK, SpongeBob
不对  非常有事
No, it's not OK
今天本该是我最美好的一天
This was gonna be my best day ever
要先开始做全世界最棒的工作
Starting with doing the best job in the world
到蟹堡王上班
working at the Krusty Krab
小子  你帮我解决了危机
Boy, you saved me barnacle
赶跑了那群线虫  保住了蟹堡王
the way you put the run on them nematodes
算是吧
Yeah, I guess so
但是后面我本来还要跟珊迪空手道的
But then I was gonna do karate with Sandy
没错  可你拯救了树屋
I know, but you saved the tree dome
要我说  还挺酷的
Pretty cool, if you ask me
应该吧
I suppose
可我之后本来要跟派大星去捉水母的
But then I was gonna go jellyfishing with Patrick
可那时候你
Well, but then you, uh
干啥了来着
what'd you do, again?
虽然我不想承认
And I hate to admit it
但要是你没修好我的簧片
but I suppose if you hadn't fixed my reed
音乐会肯定就办不下去了
the concert would've been a bust
知道吗  海绵宝宝
You see, SpongeBob?
重点不在于你
It's not about you
也不在于你完美的一天之类的
or your perfect day or any of those things
是这样吗
It's not?
对
No
重点在于我们
It's about us
是吗
It is?
对  因为你帮了我们大忙
Yep, and since you did such a good job
我们就要补偿你
we wanna make it up to you
是吗
You do?
跟咱说说看  你小小真心有啥愿望
So just tell us anything your little heart desires
我们帮你实现
and it's yours
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
今晚  裤头村音乐演奏家隆重呈现
Tonight, the Bikini Bottom players proudly present
一场超贵演出  主题是最美好的一天
a very expensive production of the best day ever
最好精彩点  花了我不少钱呢
And it better be good, for all it's costin' me
蟹堡王
我的完美工作
My perfect job
开启我完美一天
Starts my perfect day
然后来放松  快活一起玩
Then it's time to kick back, relax and play
那不在预算之内
That wasn't in the budget
一起唱  听歌声美满
Sing along, hear that happy sound
别让刺耳音符害你反感
Don't let those sour notes bring you down
高潮要来了
That's where it's at
我不报销那个
I'm not payin' for that
最美好的
一天
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
最美好的一天
It's the best day ever
美好一天
Best day ever
我们还得唱多久
How long do we have to keep this up?
唱到他小小真心没力气就好  章鱼哥
Just till his little heart gives out, Squidward
唱到他小小真心没力气就好
Just till his little heart gives out
口香糖的礼物
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
创意总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
好朋友节  好朋友节
Best friends day, best friends day
派大星
Patrick
好朋友节快
Happy best friend-
这坨口香糖是我最爱的宝贝
This chewing gum is my most beloved possession
我要把它送给我最最好的朋友
And I'm givin' it to my bestest friend
当作好朋友节的礼物
on best friends day
派大星  我
Patrick, I am
真的很荣幸  而且
Truly honored, and
怎么了  兄弟
What's wrong, buddy?
你送了我这么神的礼物
You got me such an amazing gift
我送你的却只有
and all I got you was
那个
That
你好  我是机宝2.1
Greetings, I am robo 2.1
你的贴身机器佣人
your personal robot servant
我能熟练提供二十五万多种物质享受
I am proficient in providing
over 250,000 creature comforts
要吃油酥糕点吗
Would you care for a pastry?
好吃
Yum
又甜又热又多汁
Sweet, hot and juicy
海绵宝宝  你这礼物真棒
SpongeBob, this is a great gift
多谢夸奖  派大星
Thanks for your appreciation, Patrick
但它没又大又老又旧的口香糖球好
but it's no giant, old, used ball of gum
别对自己这么苛刻  海绵宝宝
Don't be so hard on yourself, SpongeBob
我爱我的礼物
I love my gift
说真的  我现在就要去跟它玩呢
In fact, I'll go play with it right now
走吧  机宝
Come on, robo
来了  派大星主人
Coming, master Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你不介意我跟糖糖告别吧
You don't mind if I say good-bye to gummy, do you?
完全不介意
No, not at all
谢了
Thanks
再见  糖糖
Good-bye, gummy
对海绵宝宝好一点  听见没
You be good to SpongeBob, you hear?
我也爱你  糖糖
I love you, too, gummy
他归你了
Welp, he's all yours
既伟大又被人狠狠嚼过的糖糖啊
O, majestic and much-masticated gummy
虽然我不配出现在你面前
although I am not worthy to be in your presence
但愿我的寒舍能令你满意
may my humble abode please you
你真是个大块头啊
You sure are a big boy, aren't you?
知道要怎么收拾了
I know how to handle this
打点空手道就行
With a little karate
糖糖  你这摆饰当得可真漂亮啊
Gummy, what a beautiful centerpiece you make
里面有你的
With your
脏袜子  和用过的牙刷
dirty sock, and used toothbrush
苍蝇  还有发霉的
flies, and moldy
匹萨
pizza
冷静一点  海绵宝宝
Get ahold of yourself, SpongeBob
没那么糟的
It's not so bad
毕竟这可是派大星的礼物
After all, it is a gift from Patrick
你
You're
不是
not
派大星
Patrick
对不起  派大星
I'm sorry, Patrick
你的礼物必须滚
but your gift has got to go
再见  臭球
Good-bye, stink ball
再也不见
See you never
海绵宝宝  你干嘛
Hey, SpongeBob, what ya doing?
他似乎要把糖糖丢掉
It appears that he's throwing gummy away
什么  有这回事吗
What, is that true?
才不会呢  派大星
No way, Patrick
那你要怎么解释这个
Well, then how do you explain this?
是这样的  我喜欢糖糖
Well, you see, I liked gummy
就想着要给它打扮一下
and I decided to dress him up
这样子是不是很可爱啊
Isn't this a cute look?
胆大  却又低调
Bold, yet understated
真是个好点子  海绵宝宝
A brilliant idea, SpongeBob
再接再厉
Keep up the good work
走了  机宝
Come on, robo
来多找点肚脐眼绒毛吧
Let's find more bellybutton lint
好  没派大星的影子
OK, no sign of Patrick
最好速战速决
Better make this fast
准备好入土吧  糖糖
Get ready for your dirt nap, gummy
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你干什么
What are you doing?
我等着呢
I'm waiting
我在挖洞
I was digging a hole
这样就能更好地欣赏糖糖了
So I could get a better view of gummy
它可真迷人啊
'cause he is so attractive
让我来演示一下
Allow me to demonstrate
看吧  派大星
See, Patrick?
下面这个视角可美了
The view is beautiful down here
对啊  这视角看它确实挺华丽的
Yeah, he does look rather dashing from this angle
即便如此
Be that as it may
糖糖也必须得体大方地放出来
gummy must be displayed properly and proudly
我知道放哪里刚刚好
And I know just the place
放那边是不是很壮观啊
Isn't he breath-taking up there?
海绵宝宝  该走了
All righty, SpongeBob, we gotta go
我要学着用叉子
I'm gonna learn how to use a fork
对吧  机宝
right, robo?
那将是我的荣幸  主人
'Twill be my pleasure, master
顺带一提  你家样子好看了一百万倍
By the way, your house looks a million times better
谢了
Thanks
我该怎么办  小蜗
What am I gonna do, Gary?
它丑死了
It's hideous
一厢情愿  小蜗
Wishful thinking, Gary
哪个小偷会想偷那种玩意
What burglar would want to steal that thing?
你是谁
Who are you?
你哪来的
Where did you come from?
上面
Up there?
感谢海神王
Thank Neptune
大伙儿  我找到出口了
Hey, guys, I found a way out
快来
come on
我自由了
I'm free
我无糖了
I'm sugar-free
怎么一回事
What in tarnation?
我的天啊  海绵宝宝
Oh, my gosh, SpongeBob
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝  开门啊
SpongeBob, open up
珊迪
Sandy
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
看来我碰上了一点点
Looks like I got myself into a
黏人的问题
pretty sticky situation
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh
你困在上面多久了  海绵宝宝
How long you been stuck there, SpongeBob?
一整天
All day
你的老朋友珊迪会把你砍下来
Well, your old pal Sandy knows how to cut you down
不要
No
慢着  珊迪
Wait, Sandy
你越碰它  它就越生气
The more you touch it, the angrier it gets
胡说八道
That's just crazy talk
早说了吧
Told ya
你自保吧  珊迪
Save yourself, Sandy
快逃吧  免得你最后的结局变成
Run away before you end up like
我这样
me
拜托  肯定有办法
Come on, now, there's gotta be a way
我有个办法
I've got an idea
抓紧了  海绵宝宝
Hang on tight, SpongeBob
好吧
Yeah, all righty
快开啊你  老蓝
Come on, ol' blue
不许跟我顶嘴
Don't you talk back to me
乖乖听话
Do as you're told
听话
Do it
快给我听话
Come on, now, do it
快
Come on
怎么
What the?
还是别去管了  章鱼哥
Just let it go, Squidward
别去管
Let it go
不要掺和进去  章鱼哥
Don't get involved, Squidward
果然
Of course
我没事
I'm OK
这怎么回事
What's this?
海绵宝宝  你干了什么好事
SpongeBob, what have you done?
派大星  我可以解释
Now Patrick, I can explain
这  这
It's, it's
真是太神了
It's amazing
就好像是个糖糖仙境
It's like a gummy wonderland
真希望我能玩得这么快活
I wish I were havin' this much fun
我就知道你会喜欢
I knew you'd love it
派大星  我有话要跟你说
Patrick, I have something to tell you
你是否需要按摩  主人
Would you care for a massage, master?
给我得了
Enough already
你刚刚说啥了  海绵宝宝
So you were saying something, SpongeBob?
那个
Well
要怎么说好呢
how can I put this?
有话直说嘛  我
Just come right out and-
能不能别闹了
Will you stop?
不准闹
Just stop
要说就快说  海绵宝宝
Get on with it, SpongeBob
快点说完
Wrap it up
章鱼哥
Squidward?
珊迪
Sandy?
除了我  大家都在跟我的糖糖开心玩
Gee, everyone is havin' fun with my gummy but me
我  我是说你的糖糖
I, I mean your gummy
派大星  你想念你的糖糖吗
Patrick, do you miss your gummy?
今天还是好朋友节
Well, it's still best friends day
要不要把糖糖要回去呢
How would you like your gummy back?
好
Yes
糖糖归你了  兄弟
It's yours, buddy
但你得先把我们救出来
But first you gotta get us out of this
那简单
Well, that's easy
就说很简单吧
Told you it was easy
裤头村
这就是史上最棒的好朋友节
This is the best best friends day ever